sprachcaffe.com 2017-12-12

# Privacy Policy | Sprachcaffe

This privacy policy applies to this website [www.sprachcaffe.com](https://www.sprachcaffe.com/) and [www.sprachcaffe.co.uk](https://www.sprachcaffe.co.uk/) and governs the privacy of their users. These websites are served for the company HOLIDAY-N-ADVENTURE LIMITED who trade as Sprachcaffe Languages PLUS. Payments are processed by **SCIH LIMITED, 135 Kings Road, Bn1 2HX, Brighton, UK** on behalf on HOLIDAY-N-ADVENTURE LIMITED. 

The policy sets out the different areas where user privacy is concerned and outlines the obligations & requirements of the users, the website and website owners. Furthermore the way this website processes, stores and protects user data and information will also be detailed within this policy.

 **The Website**

This website and its owners take a proactive approach to user privacy and ensure the necessary steps are taken to protect the privacy of its users throughout their visiting experience. This website complies to all UK national laws and requirements for user privacy. User data is not sold to third parties.

 **Information we may collect from you**

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Information that you provide in order to make a class booking or travel booking or any other purchase via this Website.
  * Information you provide in order to enter a competition or promotion via this Website, or if you report a problem with this Website.
  * If we ask you for your contact details for future marketing use, although you have the option to opt-out of such use.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through this Site and of the fulfilment of your bookings.
  * Details of your visits to this Website (including, but not limited to, traffic data and location data) whether this is required for our own purposes or otherwise, and the resources that you access.

 **Security**

We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected. 

Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon in the address bar of your web browser, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page. The sensitive information is protected using Secure Socket Layer (SSL), the industry standard for secure web payments.

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. 

 **IP Addresses**

We may collect information about your computer including, where available, your IP address, operating system and browser type for system administration. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

 **Use of Cookies**

This website uses cookies to better the users experience while visiting the website. Users are advised that if they wish to deny the use and saving of cookies from this website on to their computers hard drive they should take necessary steps within their web browsers security settings to block all cookies from this website and its external serving vendors.

This website uses tracking software to monitor its visitors to better understand how they use it. This software is provided by Google Analytics which uses cookies to track visitor usage. The software will save a cookie to your computers hard drive in order to track and monitor your engagement and usage of the website, but will not store, save or collect personal information.

 **Contact & Communication**

Users contacting this website and/or its owners do so at their own discretion and provide any such personal details requested at their own risk. Your personal information is kept private and stored securely until a time it is no longer required or has no use, as detailed in the Data Protection Act 1998. Every effort has been made to ensure a safe and secure form to email submission process but advise users using such form to email processes that they do so at their own risk.

This website and its owners use any information submitted to provide you with further information about the products / services they offer or to assist you in answering any questions or queries you may have submitted. This includes using your details to subscribe you to any email newsletter program the website operates but only if this was made clear to you and your express permission was granted when submitting any form to email process. Or whereby you the consumer have previously purchased from or enquired about purchasing from the company a product or service that the email newsletter relates to. This is by no means an entire list of your user rights in regard to receiving email marketing material. Your details are not passed on to any third parties.

 **Email Newsletter**

This website operates an email newsletter program, used to inform subscribers about products and services supplied by this website. Users can subscribe through an online automated process should they wish to do so but do so at their own discretion. Some subscriptions may be manually processed through prior written agreement with the user.

Subscriptions are taken in compliance with UK Spam Laws detailed in the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003. All personal details relating to subscriptions are held securely and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. No personal details are passed on to third parties nor shared with companies / people outside of the company that operates this website.

Email marketing campaigns published by this website or its owners may contain tracking facilities within the actual email. Subscriber activity is tracked and stored in a database for future analysis and evaluation. Such tracked activity may include; the opening of emails, forwarding of emails, the clicking of links within the email content, times, dates and frequency of activity [this is not a comprehensive list].  
This information is used to refine future email campaigns and supply the user with more relevant content based around their activity.

In compliance with UK Spam Laws and the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003 subscribers are given the opportunity to un-subscribe at any time through an automated system. This process is detailed at the footer of each email campaign. If an automated un-subscription system is unavailable clear instructions on how to un-subscribe will by detailed instead.

 **Social Media Platforms**

Communication, engagement and actions taken through external social media platforms that this website and its owners participate on are custom to the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policies held with each social media platform respectively.

Users are advised to use social media platforms wisely and communicate / engage upon them with due care and caution in regard to their own privacy and personal details. This Website nor its owners will ever ask for personal or sensitive information through social media platforms and encourage users wishing to discuss sensitive details to contact them through primary communication channels such as by telephone or email.

This Website may use social sharing buttons which help share web content directly from web pages to the social media platform in question. Users are advised before using such social sharing buttons that they do so at their own discretion and note that the social media platform may track and save your request to share a web page respectively through your social media platform account.

Privacy policy created May 2015 by **SCIH LIMITED, 135 Kings Road, Bn1 2HX, Brighton, UK.**
